In our first video, we shared what Project Lit Bronx is and why it's important.
In this video, you'll learn everything you need to know about how to put on a community
book club in 10 easy steps.
Number one, get the books.
You can secure books through school funds, donations, and donations.
or crowdfunding sites like DonorsChoose.
We normally order 30 to 35 books.
Number two, set the date.
Once you have the books in hand,
choose the date for your book club.
We like to give participants about a month
to read each book.
Number three, pass out the books.
Now, you're ready to.
Pass out books to any and all interested students,
staff, family, and community members.
Number four, ask participants to create trivia questions.
These are questions that can be answered
by anyone who's read the book.
They're usually right there types of questions.
Number five, send out reminders.
As it gets closer to the date,
start to remind.
participants. We like to email everyone who has taken a book, put up flyers
around the school, and make announcements on our school's PA system.
Basketball? Do you love to rhyme? Then the Crossover by Kwame Alexander is the book
for you. Join us for our next Project Lit Foot Club next Thursday. You can get a
copy of The Crossover after school from Ms. Iboza Kinabe or Ms. Al-Dubai.
Number six, prepare student facilitators.
We try to make sure that all of our book clubs
are facilitated by students.
So usually a day or two before we meet,
we gather the facilitators and prepare them for their role.
This usually means reviewing the agenda
and having students decide which parts of the program
they want to facilitate.
Number seven, prepare all of the needed documents and snacks.
Now.
time to prepare everything you need for your book club. Make sure you have a
sign-in sheet, an agenda for each participant, a discussion guide, a list of
your 10 trivia questions and answers, trivia answer sheets for teams, trivia
point trackers for facilitators, prizes for the winning trivia team. These can be
books, gift cards, you name it, and of course, snacks.
Number eight, start the book club discussion. Enjoy the small and whole
group discussion time.
Good afternoon guys!
Happy New Year!
So we are three facilitators.
Number nine, wrap it up with trivia and a raffle. After small group and whole
group discussion, it's time for some fun. The facilitators ask the trivia
questions and teams race to get there.
answers into the judges number 10 take a picture when all is said and done we
always end our project lit book clubs with a group picture to document our
experience and share on social media we hope this video was helpful and
with you the 10 steps we take to put on a project-lit book club. Our next video
will focus on how we get the word out to students, staff, family, and community
members. We hope you enjoy it.